Finding Aid for Alpha Omega Alpha, Alpha Chapter of Michigan, records, 1907-1967
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Alpha Omega Alpha, Alpha Chapter of Michigan, Records 1907-1967
Alpha Omega Alpha. Alpha Chapter of Michigan
1 linear foot
91456 Bimu F41 2
Honor society at the University of Michigan Medical School. Meeting minutes, receipts, correspondence and published books of the Alpha Omega Alpha order, Alpha Chapter of Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group (Donor no. 7870 ) was received through Joel Howell, professor of internal medicine at the University of Michigan.
The record group is open to research.
Alpha Omega Alpha is a non-secret, college medical honor society. Membership in the organization is based on scholarship. Founded in 1902 by medical students at the College of Physicians and Surgeons of Chicago, subsequent chapters were organized throughout the nation. The Alpha Chapter of Michigan, founded at the University of Michigan Medical School in 1907, was the first chapter in the state of Michigan. Activities centered around an annual banquet for initiation of new members and the annual presentation of student research projects.
Correspondence and material regarding the Student Research Forum make up the bulk of the collection. Correspondence to new initiates and acceptance letters make up the bulk of the correspondence files. The Student Research Forum files consist primarily of copies of the students' presentation. Banquet programs and notebooks of minutes also document the society's activity. The primary material is supplemented by published works, including a national directory and history of Alpha Omega Alpha.
Subjects:
Alpha Omega Alpha. Alpha Chapter of Michigan.; University of Michigan--Honorary societies.; University of Michigan. Medical School.; Vaughan, Victor C. (Victor Clarence), 1851-1929.
Contributors:
Root, William, 1867-1932.
- Organizational records
  - Annual Banquet, 1959-1963, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - 1924-1945, 11 folders (Box 1)
    - 1952-1967, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Faculty Dues, 1958-1964 (Box 1)
  - Member Lists (Box 1)
  - Catalogue of the Alpha Omega Alpha Honor Fraternity 1902-1922. By William W. Root, Secretary-Treasurer, Ithaca, New York ca. 1923 (Box 1)
  - Alpha Omega Alpha Directory edited by the Office of the Assistant Secretary-Treasurer, Ithaca, New York 1936 (Box 1)
  - Minute Books
    - 1907-1911 (Box 1)
    - 1912-1921 (Box 1)
    - 1938-1940 (Box 1)
  - Questionnaire, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Student Research Forum
    - Programs, 1955-1967 (Box 1)
    - General, 1956, 1958-1967, 11 folders (Box 1)